Jose Pereiro

Physicist And Machine Learning Scientist.

Contact

Address

Cra 44 #17CS- 40 Medellin, Antioquia, 111011

Phone

3017385084

E-mail

jose_123.co.com@hotmail.c om

Skills

Bioinformatics

Excellent

Artificial intelligence

Very Good

Machine learning

Very Good

Fortran

Good

Python

Excellent

Matlab

Very Good

C

Very Good

Physicist graduated from the best university in Colombia with an emphasis in bioinformatics. I have two minors in chemistry and microbiology, I worked 3 years as an assistant in the biophysics laboratory where I was in charge of biological samples and spectroscopic instruments. In bioinformatics I was interested in data science, machine learning and artificial intelligence, I have taken various courses in Udemy, Datacamp and Unipython of machine learning. My main programming language is Python and I also know how to program in R, Matlab, C, C ++ and Fortran. I have experience in handling SQL and NoSQL databases and their analysis by means of Python packages. I have worked with artificial and convolutional neural networks for the processing and analysis of general and medical images. The packages I've mainly worked with are Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch, fastai, spaCy, sci-kit learn and scikit-image. I have worked with different predictive analytical models, data cleansing and preprocessing, data wrangling, data mining, simple and multiple linear regressions, random trees and forests. I also have experience in the academic field, I am passionate about teaching and sharing information.

Likewise, I also saw postgraduate courses at the university of systems biology, synthetic biology and membrane biophysics. The codes I worked on can be found in my physics and bioinformatics repository on GitHub.

Work History

2020-02 -Current

Lead Data Analyst

Interacpedia, Medellin, Antioquia

- Assessed exposure, compared valuations and evaluated threats to strategies.
- Developed rebalancing strategies to minimize risk exposures.
- Developed and presented proposals for new investments.
- Facilitated portfolio performance review and implemented new strategies.
- Devoted special emphasis to punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.

C++	
	Very Good
Pytorch	
	Excellent
Keras	
	Excellent
Tensorflow	
	Excellent
Fastai	
	Excellent
Spanish	
	Excellent
English	
	Excellent
Neural networks	<u> </u>
Neural Herworks	Excellent
	LACGIIGI II
German	A
	Average
Image processing	
	Excellent
CNN	
	Very Good
R	
	Excellent

2016-01 -2019-01

Biophysics Laboratory Assistant

Universidad De Los Andes, Bogota, Capital district

- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time.
- Devoted special emphasis to punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.

Education

2014-06 -2019-04

Bachelor of Science: Physics

Universidad De Los Andes - Bogota

- Thesis: Study of the resistance to desiccation associated with biofilm formation in Pseudomonas fluorescens with FTIR spectroscopy. (Thesis in biophysics)
- Graduated in Top 1% of Class
- Minored in Chemistry
- Minored in Microbiology
- Majored in Physics with an emphasis on bioinformatics.
- Complete Machine learning course Udemy.
 Image Processing in Python Udemy.
 Image Processing with Keras in Python Datacamp.
 Biomedical Image Analysis in Python Datacamp.
 Introduction to Deep Learning with Pytorch Datacamp.

Introduction to TensorFlow in Python - Datacamp. Introduction to Natural Language Processing in Python - Datacamp.

Advanced NLP with spaCy - Datacamp.

Supervised Learning with scikit-learn - Datacamp.